# **Taylor Simpson**

<u>taylor.daniel.simpson@gmail.com</u> taylorsimpson.ca • linkedin.com/in/td-simpson

### **SUMMARY**

Product Designer with 5+ years of experience bringing user-centered digital products to life. With a foundation in product management, UX, and a technical background, I take a detail-oriented, collaborative approach to solving real user problems. Working across the full product lifecycle – from research and strategy to design, launch, and continuous iteration, I have a passion for delivering engaging and intuitive experiences.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Product Designer

Social Good Fund

Remote

Social Good Fund is a 501(c)(3) fiscal sponsor that supports mission-aligned projects with operational infrastructure. I'm part of a small cross-functional team working on one of their internally led initiatives: an iOS/ Android app designed to connect individuals seeking help with those offering support – whether through their time, skills, or donations.

- Delivering comprehensive UX specs including user flows, wireframes, and copy that address core use cases, edge cases, and usability pain points. This has reduced the time from concept to launch by 40%.
- Collaborating closely with engineers and contributing my own code updates for minor UX and copy updates via Git, reducing implementation time for bugs and improvements by 20%.
- Owning in-app copy and contributing to marketing content ensuring consistent, user-centred messaging across platforms to increase user comprehension and engagement.
- Conducting regression testing, logging bugs / UX issues in Linear, resulting in reduced downtime and user-reported errors by 60%.
- Built and maintain the marketing website in WordPress, helping improve traffic and ad performance through SEO and A/B testing

Product Manager Sept. 2020 – Aug. 2023
Lexir Remote

Lexir is a B2B distribution and e-commerce SaaS platform for craft wine and spirit brands. It enables brands from around the world to enter the European market in a simplified way, providing tools and support for importation, warehousing, e-commerce integrations, last-mile delivery, analytics, and local sales partner connections.

- Led the development and release of Lexir's brand dashboard and e-commerce platform
- Built the go-to-market strategy, product roadmap, and developed key brand messaging
- Conducted user research, A/B tested, and translated requirements for a design and dev team of 5
- Regularly met with client brands and used data-driven insights to improve Lexir's offerings
- Created and managed marketing campaigns across various channels including email, social media, ads, blogs, events, SEO, influencer marketing, and community outreach
- Grew the client base by 8x and scaled the platform from 1 market to 6 markets in Europe
- Reduced implementation costs by 60% by streamlining development methods

Product Manager

Sept. 2018 – Apr. 2019

Pedal Patrol

Kingston, Ontario

- Led a cross-functional team, designing, and developing a working prototype for a mobile app that reunites cyclists with their stolen bikes through crowdsourcing. Built with React Native for iOS and Android.
- Managed the team and client through the full product lifecycle from ideation to delivery
- The prototype was transitioned to a non-profit in Vancouver to continue its development

Content Strategist Apr. 2018 – Mar. 2019
QHacks Kingston, Ontario

- Developed and implemented marketing strategies for the biggest university event post-orientation week, attracting 1200+ applicants and \$100k+ in sponsorships
- Led external communications of the brand, writing, and editing copy for the website, dashboard, handbooks, emails, and ads
- Created the brand's first content style guide used by a team of 20 (and still used today)

### Software Developer Orange Gate Consulting

May 2018 – Dec. 2018

Toronto, Ontario

- Spearheaded a new company department researching and developing new applications for consumer robots.
   As a result, Orange Gate shifted its business focus to robot applications which are used in the financial services and automotive industries
- Created wireframes, user flows, and scripts based on leading practices in visual and conversational UX
- Built functional prototypes with Java, Kotlin, XML, JavaScript, and Node.js, using agile methodologies
- Presented prototypes to C-Suite client executives in Canada and the USA

## Student Ambassador, Growth

Sept 2016 - Apr. 2017

Kingston, Ontario

Grabb MobilePromoted a new food-ordering application expanding into a new market

- Increased adoption and customer engagement through campus events and social media
- Met with restaurant owners to discuss online ordering solutions for their locations

#### **EDUCATION & PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT**

Queen's University 2015 – 2019

## Bachelor of Computing, Computer Science, Specialization in Software Design

Kingston, ON

- Teaching Assistant: Artificial Intelligence (CISC 352)
- Marketing Commissioner: Computing Students' Association

# Smith School of Business at Queen's University

2016 - 2020

Certificate in Business

Kingston, ON

**BrainStation Toronto UX Design Certificate** 

**2023 – 2024** Toronto, ON

#### **SKILLS**

- Technical Skills: Python, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, Java, React.js, Node.js, Git, SQL, Jira, Linear, Confluence, Figma, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe XD, Microsoft Suite
- Other Skills: Data Analysis, Go-to-Market Strategy, Prototyping, Wireframing, Agile Development, Product Roadmapping, UX Design, Product Lifecycle Management, Digital Marketing, Marketing Analytics, Marketing Strategy, Market Planning, Marketing Campaigns, Copywriting

#### **ADDITIONAL INFO**

- Awards:
  - o People's Choice in Human-Computer Interaction Queen's Creative Computing Showcase (2018)
  - o Top 4 Hack Hack the 6ix (2017)
- Fun Achievements:
  - o Game Show Winner Splatalot
  - o Silver Medalist Canada East Short Track Speed Skating Championship
  - o Guinness World Record Largest Rubik's Cube Mosaic